Bring him here.
把他带这来
In the time of our ancestors
在我们祖先那时候
the cycle of our people lay in the hands of the children.
我们族人的循环再世位置就在孩子的手中
A child's position in the tribe was left to the maker.
在部落中孩子是造物主留下的
Children bearing marks were brought before the elders
孩子的方位标志显现要早于大人
there, they were given titles...
这儿，它们是被赐予的标记
...titles that would last a lifetime.
这些标记将跟随他一生
Wisdom...
智慧
Courage...
勇气
Vision.
想象力
This boy holds the holy marks
这个孩子有着我们祖先
of our ancestors.
神圣的标记
He is a leader.
他会是个领导者
He is a prophet.
他会是个先知
We should listen to him.
我们应该听从他
I see you!
我看见你了
Nat?
纳特
All right, you win again.
好吧，你又赢了
Come on out!
出来
Sam? You come on in here for supper!
萨姆？过来吃晚饭了
Yessum.
好的
Bye, nat.
再见，纳特
Bye.
再见
You so much as bat an eye,
你就像蝙蝠的眼睛
I'm gonna blow you from here to hell.
我要把你从这打回地狱去
What you doin' out here, boy?
你在外面做什么，伙计？
Pickin' up some food for my master,
从我的主人那装点食物
Benjamin Turner.
本杰明 特纳
In the middle of the night? Turn around.
在午夜时间？转过来
here your pass at?
你的通行许可在哪？
Bring it on. C'mon! Bring it!
拿过来，快点
Get back.
退回去
You think you're smarter than me, don't you, boy?
你觉得你比我聪明，是不是？
No, sir.
没有，先生
Jesse, who do we call a nigger
杰西，我们怎么叫黑鬼的
who done think he can outsmart a white man?
谁会觉得他比一个白人更精明？
A dead nigger.
死了的黑鬼
Turn around.
转过来
On your knees.
跪下
You done this to yourself, boy.
这是你自己找的
- What happened?  - Go on to bed.
- 发生什么了？ － 上床去
I got caught stealing food.
我偷食物被抓了
I killed a slave catcher. I gotta go.
我杀了看守，我得逃走了
You take care of your mom and Nana, you hear?
你照顾好你母亲和娜娜，知道吗？
You a child of god.
你是神的孩子
You got purpose. It's in you.
你意志坚定
The lord put it there,
上帝把它放在了这
and there ain't nothing nobody can do to take it away.
没有任何人和事可以把它们夺走
You hear?
你明白了？
Yes, sir.
是的
Now you go ahead on and go to bed.
现在你上床去
I'll be back for y'all as soon as I can.
我可能快点回来
Go on back to bed. Go on to bed, girl! We sleep!
回床上去，我们睡觉
Bridget! Nancy! Y'all wake up!
布里奇特，南希，起来了
Isaac's in a lot of trouble.
艾萨克有大麻烦了
I need one of y'all to tell me where he is.
我需要你们当中的人告诉我他去哪里了
Don't know where he is, massa. We ain't seen him all night.
不知道去哪了，主人，我们一晚没见他
You sure?
你确定
Ben, I'm gonna ask you to leave.
本，我命令你离开
- Huh?  - A white man has lost his life tonight.
- 嗯？ - 今晚一个白人丧命了
You know like I do what that mean. Get!
你知道这样说代表着接下去要发生什么样的事，走
Now, any harm done to these people,
现在，我要给他们些颜色看看
I'm gonna call the sheriff! I'm serious!
我要报告警长，我是认真的
None of y'all know where he is, huh?
你们没人知道他在那？
No, sir.
没有，先生
Goddamnit.
他妈的
What about you, boy?
你知道吗，孩子？
He don't know nothing, either.
他也什么不知道
Where's your daddy at?
你父亲在那？
Now listen, you don't tell me where he's at,
听着，你不告诉我他在那
someone else is gonna find him,
其它人也会找到他
and they gonna kill him.
他们会杀了他
You tell me, I'll go get him.I'll bring him back here safe.
你告诉我，我会安全把他带回来
All right?
好吗？
Tell me where daddy's at.
告诉我你父亲在哪
Say it. Spit something outta that mouth! Say it!
说话，不要一言不发
Tell me where he's at!
告诉我在哪
Goddamnit.
他妈的
You that nigger's boy, all right.
你是那个黑鬼的孩子，好吧
If I find out y'all's been lying,
如果让我发现你在说谎
I'm gonna come back here, i ain't gonna be so nice...
我会再回来的，到时我就不客气了
Oh, massa, please! Please! Massa, please! Oh, lord!
主人，不要，不要，上帝啊！
All right, that's... That's enough! Stop!
够了，住手
You best teach that boy some manners.
你最好教教那个孩子礼貌
Next time he look me in the eye,
下次，他要用眼睛看着我
you gonna get the same thing what waitin' for his pa.
你父亲也会是这个结果
Mind if I help you?
可以帮你吗？
No, ma'am.
不用了
Samuel told me something this morning
萨缪尔告诉我早上的事情了
I wanted to ask you about.
我想要向你打听下
He said, nat knows how to read.
他说纳特知道怎么读
Nat don't not know how to read.
纳特不知道怎么读
Part of me couldn't believe it myself.
做为我自己是不相信的
So I tested him.
所以我测试了他
Sure enough,
十分肯定
there he was sounding out letters.
他就在哪大声朗读
You have him come by the house tomorrow after lunch.
你明天午饭后把他带来
He don't mean no harm.
他没有恶意
I'ma whip him good the next time I see him.
下次我看见他我会抽他一顿
Whip him? Nonsense.
抽他？不要
I'm gonna teach him.
我要教育他
If the good lord gave that boy a gift to read,
如果万能的主给了这个孩子阅读的能力
we'd be remiss to let it go to waste.
我们就不应该怠慢它，浪费它
And don't expect him back anytime soon.
你不要希望他能任何时候都能回家
He'll be living with us in the main house for a while.
他会和我们在主屋一起生活一段时间
Lessons best not be disturbed in the beginning.
课程最好在开始时就不要被打断
Yes, ma'am.
好的，夫人
It's okay, baby. It's okay. It ain't real.
没关系，孩子，不是真的
It ain't real. It's all right. It's in your mind.
不是真的，没事了，它在你的心里
It's in your mind.
它在你的心里
Momma's here now.
妈妈在这
Want my poppa.
我要父亲
Me too, baby.
我也是的，孩子
Me too.
我也是
Put your arms through.
把你的手臂穿过去
How handsome.
多帅气
He'll be all right.
他会没事的
These books are for white folks.
这些书是给白人看的
They're full of things your kind wouldn't understand.
这里有着你无法理解的全部事情
But I do have a special one just for you.
但是我会让你读一本特别的书
And guess what?
你猜是什么？
It's the best book ever written.
是有史以来最好的一本书
You're a special boy, Nathaniel.
你是个特别的孩子
Study hard and heed my instructions, hear?
努力学习听从我的指令，知道吗？
Your life,
你的人生
it'll never be the same.
将会与众不同
I'll see to that.
我能预见到
Yes, missus.
是，太太
"Genesis. In the beginning..."
创世纪，开始
In the beginning...
开始
Here, this word here, "the."
这儿，这个词是这儿
That's tricky. Now, these letters "t-h."
那是狡猾，机警
Whenever you see them...
无论何时你看见他们
"...cleanse your hands, ye sinners...
洁净你的双手，罪人们
"And purify your hearts, ye double-minded.
心怀二意的人们，净化你们的心灵
"Be afflicted, and mourn, and weep.
被折磨，悲哀，哭泣
"Let your laughter be turned to mourning,
让你的笑声变成了悲哀
"and your joy to heaviness."
和你的快乐变成忧伤
James 4, chapter 8 and 9.
雅各书，第四章，第八至九篇
Turn with me, if you would, to James 1.
随我翻到雅各书第一章
Holding on to the goodness of the lord.
握着耶和华的恩惠
I spoke to Ben, before he went on to be with the lord.
在他去陪伴上帝之前，我曾对本说
He felt you'd be more useful to our family as a field hand.
他觉得你作为一个农场工人会对我们家庭更有用
I'm sorry, nat.
我很抱歉，纳特
Now, you gonna start here,
现在，你要从这开始
and you're gonna work your way down yonder.
你要去远一点的地方开始工作
And I'll be right over here. You hear?
而我会在这里，明白吗？
Ah!
嗯
Thank you, brother.
谢谢你，兄弟
I had fainted, unless I had believed to see,
我已经不省人事了，除非我有看见
the goodness of the lord
上帝的善良
in the land of the living.
在我们生活的土地上
Wait on the lord,
等待上帝的到来
be of good courage,
要变的善良勇敢
and he shall strengthen thine heart.
他会使你的内心强大
Wait, I say,
等会，我说
on the lord.
依靠上帝
Let us bow our heads.
让我们低下我们的头颅
Sam, that sister of yours,
萨姆，那是你姐姐？
gonna make a fine wife indeed.
真是能成为个好老婆
It's been a true blessing
我说的是真的
seeing her develop into the woman that she is.
看着她变成一个女人
It'd be an even better blessing
这可是个美好的祝福
seein' her and momma
看她和她的母亲
put their feet under his table instead of mine.
她们把脚放在他桌子下而不是我的
I gotta say,
我得说
Sam, your slaves sure do know how to behave.
萨姆，你的奴隶确信知道怎么守规矩
I'm impressed with them every time I come around.
每次我来都令我印象深刻
Well, they god fearin'. One of them's a preacher.
好的，他们当中有个牧师
No one's gotta tell you
没人告诉我
the times are tough with the drought.
干旱的日子真是太难熬了
It's gettin' harder for the whites in this county
在这个国家对白人来说变得更艰难了
to clothe and feed their niggers good.
要给他们的黑人奴隶吃好穿好
Talks of insurrection
这些关于暴动的谈论
got folks scared.
让白人家伙感到害怕
I think people might pay good money
我觉得人们应该付出更好的工资报酬
to have them calm down a bit.
可以让这些人能更冷静些
Especially by one of their own.
特别是一个他们自己人
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
噢
You seen a nigger run past here?
你看见一个黑鬼从这跑过吗？
Naw. Then again i doze off for a few.
我睡着了没看见
What about you, boy?
你看见了吗，孩子？
Best not lie now. I know when y'all's lyin'.
最好现在不要撒谎，你骗不过我的
No, sir.
没有，先生
Couple of niggers went missin'
两个比尔琼斯地方的
off bill Johnson's place this mornin'.
黑鬼不见了今天早上
Say they raised up on an overseer
说是在逃跑之前
before they took off.
他们举起了工头
All right, you see somethin' let us know.
好的，看见什么就告诉我
Will do.
好的
Giddyup.
驾
You finish up here, I'll go square up inside.
你把这里结束了，我去广场里面
Yes, sir.
好的，先生
Ma'am. The youngin', he dropped this a step back.
夫人，杨斯掉了这个
Thank ya.
谢谢
Whatcha think you're doin'?
你在干什么那？
He was just tryin'... You spoke to my wife.
他只是…你和我妻子说话了
Where's your owner, boy?
你主人在那？
I asked you a question.
问你话那
You best goin' to put that stick down now!
你最好收起你的棍子来
I want the sheriff.
我要找警长了
his boy assaulted me!
这个家伙羞辱了我
He assaulted my wife!
他羞辱了我妻子
And I'm bringin' charges!
我要指控他
Sheriff Floyd?
弗洛伊德警长？
All right, you fetch him if you like.
好的，他归你了，如果你喜欢
But in the meantime i will give you
但同时我数三下
to the count of three to put your stick down
你把棍子放下来
before I give you some real charges
在我给你一些真实的指控之前
to give him when he gets here.
让他回到这里
You threatnin' me?
你威胁我
One.
一
Two.
二
C'mon, get the boy.
走吧，带着孩子
Let's get home.
回家
We got sweet corn!
我们的玉米很甜
C'mon now! Get your grits!
来吧，来点玉米粉
We got sweet corn here.
我们这玉米很甜
Here you go.
看一看
And this one here!
在这的这个
Strong as an ox!
强壮如牛
Nothin' but good seed flowin' from this here buck.
虽然不起眼，但是年轻的体内流动着活力的种子
Look at them teeth. Huh?
看看他们的牙齿
I'll start him out at...
我将开始拍卖
200.
两百
150?
一百五
C'mon now, I gotta make a living here, gents.
拜托了，我还得在这接着混那
100? 75?
一百？七十五？
Sold! Get outta here.
成交，带走吧
Put a yoke on him. Bring her up here.
给他套上束具，带那个女过来
Now, consider this comely wench.
现在，大家可以考虑下这个标致的乡下妞
Not a day over 18.
不超过十八岁
All right, I'll start her off at 175.
好吧，我从一百七十五元开始起拍
I got 175. Do I hear two?
我出一百七十五元，还有出价的吗？
Now we're talkin'! Do I got 225?
现在出价两百二十五了
Massa, that wench there sure would make
主人，那个乡下女孩可以当作礼物送给
a good weddin' gift for miss Catherine.
凯瑟琳小姐
225!
两百二十五
You keep sayin' she been askin'.
你一直在说小姐在问你
Do I hear 250?
你出两百五吗？
She looks right young, if you ask me.
她看着十分年轻，如果你问我的话
C'mon now.
快点！
You right, sir, she young. Gimme 250.
对的，先生，她很年轻，给我两百五
C'mon. But with the right teacher,
但是如果跟对人的话
- a wench like that?  - 250.
- 一个像这样的姑娘？ - 两百五
Could be workin' a long time.
可以工作很长一段时间了
There it is! 275?
两百七十五元
Massa, sure would be a shame to watch her
主人，我们应该
go to waste for such a low price.
用一个低价买了她
And what the hell would you know about
你知道个屁
what's a little and what's a lot, huh?
什么是高什么是低？
I don't know what's gotten into you lately,
我不知道你最近怎么了
but whatever it is, you better quit.
但不论是什么，你最好放弃
Are you seein' what I'm seein'?
你看见我看到的了吗？
You take this one home, you know,
你带着个回家
clean her up,
把她洗干净了
won't be long before you find yourself
不要太久
happier than a dog with three balls!
你会比玩球的小狗还要高兴的
Smile, bitch.
笑一笑，贱货
That's 250 goin' once.
两百五一次
250 goin' twice.
两百五两次
- 275  - 275.
- 两百七十五  - 两百七十五
We got 275!
我们出两百七十五
275 goin' once.
两百七十五一次
275 goin' twice.
两百七十五两次
Sold to that fine gentleman in the back!
卖给后排那个善良的绅士了
Whoa.
喔
She be fine, sir.
她没事的，先生
I sure hope you're right.
我希望你是对的
Have your momma get her cleaned and fed.
你妈给她洗过吃了
- Start breakin' her in.  - Yes, sir.
- 先从擦地板开始  - 明白，先生
You and hark can start on the north fence
你和汉克可以从北面围栏那开始
- first thing in the morning.  - Yes, sir.
- 这是明早的第一件事  - 明白，先生
I ain't gonna hurt you.
我不会伤害你的
Just gonna climb up and help you out.
只是爬上来帮你出来
It's all right.
没事的
Who is this child? What happened?
这孩子是谁？发生了什么？
Burnin' up.
活力四射
This mine! This my dress! My dress! This my dress!
是我的，这是我的裙子
Go now! Get out, ya!
走开，出去
We're not gonna hurt you. We're not gonna hurt you.
我们不会伤害你
Don't take it away.
不要带走
You just smile
笑一下
and let them do the talkin'. All right?
让他们可以谈话，好吗？
Yessum.
好的
Afternoon, massa. This here cherry-Ann.
中午好，主人，这是切瑞安妮
Massa.
主人
Catherine!
凯瑟琳娜
Catherine, this here is cherry-Ann.
凯瑟琳娜，这是切瑞安妮
Missus.
夫人
Oh, thank you!
谢谢你
Come on, i want you to meet momma.
来吧，见下我母亲
Momma.
母亲
Thank you.
谢谢你
For what?
为了什么
For gettin' her better. For makin' her so beautiful.
你让她边得更好更漂亮了
I didn't do nothin'.
我什么也没做
That girl was brought into this world
那些美貌
as beautiful as she could be.
都是那女孩与生俱来的
It sure is sad to see you and the missus go.
很难过看到你和太太要走了
We'll be just down the road.
我们只是隔了一条路
When we get all good and settled,
当我们都安顿好了
we'll come back and visit.
我们会回来看看的
On Sundays for church and that.
周日去教堂之后
Well, there's no rush.
好吧，不急的
Oh. I'm foolin'. Come here.
我开玩笑的，来这
If y'all need anything,
如果你有需要
or he ain't treatin' you right, you let me know.
或者他对你不好，让我知道
Yes, big brother. I love you.
是的，哥哥，我爱你
Love you, too.
我也爱你
Momma, you ready?
母亲，你准备好了吗？
I'm worried about you, Sam.
我很担心你，萨姆
This a big place to be out here all by yourself.
你要独自面对这么大的一个地方
I'll be fine.
我没事的
You take care now.
你要小心
All right. Hmm.
好的
Massa. For the horses.
主人，为马准备的
Just one.
就一个
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
Hi.
嗨
I'm nat.
我是纳特
I know.
我知道
Sorry for
不好意思
fightin' you.
打扰你了
Oh, that's fine.
没事
Um...
嗯…
They're pretty.
它们很漂亮
Found them 'round here.
在这四周发现的
Thank you.
谢谢
Bye.
再见
Just as the planted crop
就像我们在
is harvested in its own time,
收割庄稼一样
so too has the lord planted us.
主也在播种着我们
Good lord.
赞美主啊
will finish his work in us.
当我们完成了主赐予我们的工作时
So, in closing, i urge you all to take heart,
最后，我会敦促你们用心来敬奉上帝
for god is at work in your life,
要用尽你们的一生
and he will not stop until his job is done. Amen?
直到它的工作完成才算结束，阿门？
Amen. Dismissed!
阿门，解散
It seems like it's been forever
仿佛命运已经注定永远
since I last seen you.
自从我上次看见你起
There were a few miles between us.
我们之间虽只有短短的几步
Just feels like so many more.
但我却感觉到很遥远
How is it there?
在哪过的还好吗？
It's fine. Not like what I come from 'fore here.
很好，不像我以前待的地方
Most days I'm just tending to miss Elizabeth
多数时间我都是在照顾伊丽莎白小姐
or fetching this-that for miss Catherine.
要不就是给凯瑟琳娜小姐拿这拿那的
You know if y'all coming back next week for church?
如果你下周从教堂还回来的话？
I know as much as you.
我很了解你
I suppose if missus is suggesting it,
我猜想如果太太一直暗示下去
master Reese don't mind the trip.
里斯大人也不在意什么的
I sure wouldn't wanna wait another season to see ya.
我可不想等的太久才能见到你
Me, neither.
我也是的
My Nana got it from my grandaddy.
这是我奶奶从我爷爷那拿来的
She brought it with her when she was taken from Africa.
她被从非洲抓来时就一直带着它
Said it was the only thing that kept her mind free.
这是唯一能让她的心灵感到自由的东西
It's pretty.
很漂亮
I want you to have it.
我把它送给你了
In case I don't see you for a while, you
防止我有段时间不能见到你
have something that reminds you of me.
这个可以体醒你要时刻记住我
I don't know if it's right I take it.
我不知道是不是该收下
'Sides, I don't have nothing to give you
我可没有能让你
to remind you of me.
思念我的东西给你
I spend all my time thinkin' about you already.
我已经对你念念不忘了
Cherry?
切瑞？
Come help with momma. It's time to go.
来帮下妈妈，可以走了
Who there?
谁在那？
Nat?
纳特？
What are you doin'?
你要干嘛？
I shoulda done that earlier.
我应该早点这样做
You came here to kiss me?
你就是专程来亲我的？
No, no, no.
不是
I ain't got much.
我要的比这多
My faith, momma, Nana.
我的信仰，妈妈，奶奶
Up until now, enough.
直到现在，我要的更多
Cherry, I'd feel right honored if you'd be my wife.
切瑞，我希望你可以成我的妻子，我会无比的荣幸
I'd treat ya right. Protect ya with my life.
我会对你好的，用我的一生来保护你
If you'd have me.
如果你嫁给我
Yes. Yes, I will.
我愿意
What now?
接下去怎么做？
Uh...
嗯
I talk it over with Samuel.
我会和萨缪尔先生谈谈
Get us a cabin set up when y'all visit.
给我们找个小屋子，等你下次来的时候就会布置一新了
All right.
好的
Heavenly father.  We are gathered here today
天父，我们今天齐聚一堂
to join together these two children,
来参加这两个孩子的婚礼
who have found the love that exists in you.
他们找到了爱的真谛
The love that surrounds all of us all the time.
我们一直沐浴在爱的怀抱中
We bless these children together with our hands
我们祝福他们
that the love that flows through our hands...
我们手捧鲜花与爱
Well, hello, reverend.
哈喽，教士
I wasn't expecting to see you around
我没指望能在
these parts 'till Sunday.
周日见到你
What brings you around the middle of the week?
什么风把你吹来的？
Never a wrong time...
永远不要在错误的时间
...to bring a blessing to a brother in Christ.
给一个基督兄弟带来祝福
Oh lord.
噢，上帝
Is this blessing gonna cost me money?
这祝福要花钱吗？
Not a penny. To the contrary, in fact.
一个子也不要，实际从另一面来说
Isaiah, run us out a water.
艾塞亚，送点水来
Gin, if you please.
最好给我来些杜松子酒
So, I put the word out about your preacher.
我要谈下关于你牧师的情况
Got a couple of farmers willing to turn a good coin.
有几个农民愿意出好价钱
- Is that right?   - Mmm-hmm.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
Every bit counts these days.
这些天价格看涨
Oh.
哦
Ah!
啊
Mmm.
嗯…
If your boy does to their liking,
如果他能满足他们的愿望
you could get outta debt.
你能大赚一笔
Save your farm.
拯救你的农场
And all I gotta do is let nat preach.
所有这些都只要纳特牧师出面就行了
That's it.
就这么简单
Now, I'm not vouching for the character of these fellas.
我不能担保这些家伙
What business they runnin' or how.
是怎么运营这些生意的
I'm just here to tell you
我就是来告诉你
that there's an opportunity there.
有个机会可以尝试下
One you got the means to capitalize on.
你要做的就是好好利用它
Whereabouts we talkin'?
我们说的是哪里？
In southampton, at the start.
是先从南安普敦开始的
Well, sounds good enough.
好的，听起来不错
I'll send you the details.
细节我会在告诉你的
Names, locations, and dates, I'd say by tomorrow.
姓名，地点，细节，我明天告诉你
You already booked the dates.
你已经预定好时间了
I figured you'd say yes.
我就是来让你同意的
What's in it for you?
你能得到什么好处？
The pure joy of knowing that I'm helping a brother.
什么好处也没有，就是为了帮助兄弟
And, uh... Oh, here it comes.
还有，关键的来了
Well, if I was to receive a gift offering,
好吧，如果我能得到好处
I certainly wouldn't object.
我当然也不会反对的
You are caution, reverend.
你太小心了，教士
I am but a servant.
我只是个侍奉上帝的仆人
Here's some salt pork and some tomatoes
好多咸肉和西红柿
for when you get hungry.
你饿的时候可以吃
Thank you, momma.
谢谢你，母亲
Don't y'all go getting' worried now.
不要担心
I'll be back directly.
我会安全返回的
I know.
我知道
Pray the lord brings you back safe.
向上帝祈祷，你能平安返回
You massa Turner's nigger?
你是特纳家的黑鬼？
I'm nat.
我是纳特
Massa Turner's in here.
特纳在里面
Come on.
来吧
- We're here?  - Yes, sir.
- 我们到了？ - 是，先生
Sam Turner.
萨姆 特纳
Made it right on time. Joseph Randall.
真准时，约瑟芬 兰道尔
This here's abner.
这是艾伯纳
This little one? Jasper.
这小个子是杰斯帕
This the preacher? Yes, sir.
这是牧师？是的，先生
Nat?
纳特？
Evening, sir.
晚上好，先生
He's a little young, ain't he?
他看着还是个小年轻？
Why, he's old enough.
没有，他蛮大了
You've been studying the word awhile, haven't you?
他已经学习圣经很长一段时间了，是不是？
Studyin'?
学习？
I can barely train my niggers to learn their own names.
我能勉强训练我的黑奴们学习他们自己的名字
Come on!
来吧
It's hard times
这是艰难时刻
for small farmers  like you and myself.
对于我和你这些小农场主来说
Breakin' even's hard enough,
现在情况更糟糕了
but getting ahead's impossible.
黑奴要想出入头地是不可能的
So to save some,
我只能做个好人
I cut them back to a meal a day per head now.
把他们带回来每天管顿饭吃
A few of them started getting' fidgety,
他们当中有一小部分人开始变得不安躁动
so I had abner come down on 'em.
所以我让艾伯纳陪着我一起
Abner, here, he's my only real protection.
艾伯纳，这儿，他是我唯一真正的护身符
Now, they needs to mind me. You speak on that.
现在，这些黑奴让我不满意，你要和他们说
They treasure in heaven from submittin' and all.
他们所有的财富都在天堂里
If they gets to moanin' or carryin' on,
如果他们感到悲伤或是继续这样
ou don't pay 'em no mind,
我可以毫不怜悯的分文不给
because they lazy as all hell.
因为他们太懒惰了就好像生活在地狱里
They do anything to get outta work.
他们出工不出力
You ready, boy?
你准备好了吗，伙计？
Listen up! Got a preacher here tonight.
听着，今晚我请了牧师来
Come here, boy.
过来，孩子
Now, he's a nigger here like y'all,
你们看他和你们一样都是黑人
and he's here to talk to you about the lord.
他会告诉你们关于上帝的好处
So you listen to him
你们注意听着
and you might just make it into heaven, you hear?
你们照样做也可以上天堂的，知道吗？
Brothers and sisters.
兄弟姐妹
I lead you to Peter 2:18.
我带你见彼得
"Slaves, submit yourselves
奴隶们，奉献自己
"to your masters with all respect."
带着你所有的尊敬去你的主人那
"Not only to those who are good and considerate,
不仅那些好的和体贴
"but also to those who are harsh."
但那些严厉的
You sure you don't wanna stay the night?
你确定晚上不住这？
Got some fine Brandy
拿些好的白兰地来
and a couple of choice wenches in the cellar.
有几个女孩关在地窖里
Get abner here to strike out the fiddle
让艾伯纳来给我们拉小提琴
and sit around the fire, tell some old lies, huh?
让女士和我们围坐在壁炉边
No. We best be gettin' back before sun go down.
不了，我们要赶在太阳落山前回家
All right. Suit yourself.
好的，你自便吧
Would take a bottle of that Brandy,
我可以带瓶白兰地
if you could spare it.
如果你愿意分给我的话
Oh, sure thing. Abner?
哦，小事一件，艾伯纳？
I got a chocolate one here
有了那个巧克力帮我办事
that does it right every time.
我可真是省力不少啊
You sure you don't wanna stay?
你确定不要留下过夜了？
No, they expectin' us back. You know how it is.
不了，他们等着我们回去
All right.
好的
You's a smart man, Sam.
你是个聪明人，萨姆
Man make a fortune with that boy.
你带着那家伙前途光明
Great doin' business with you.
和你做生意很愉快
Let's go.
走吧
You all right?
你还好吗？
Yeah.
S
The dress there.
那边的那件衣服
That the one you were wearing that day?
是你婚礼时穿过的吧？
Yes.
对的
Momma offered you one of hers?
是妈妈从她衣服里选给你的吗？
She did.
是的
"Abigail hayne."
阿比盖尔 海恩
My momma.
我的母亲
"Madison hayne." Who was that?
麦迪森海恩，那是谁？
That's me.
是我
My momma,
我母亲
she put this dress on me
她给我穿上这件裙子的时候
the day they took me from her.
他们把我从她身边夺走了
Showed me this here patch.
看见这块补丁
Told me to never forget who I was,
它提醒着我永远不要忘了我是谁
and that I had a momma.
还有我的母亲
And that she was somewhere,
她就在某个地方
missing me and loving me.
我时刻都在思念着她，爱着她
I was 13.
我那时十三岁
I can call ya Madison, if ya like.
如果愿意我可以叫你麦迪森
You can call me whatever you want.
只要你喜欢，怎么叫都行
I'll call you queen.
你是我的皇后
What's wrong?
有什么不对吗？
We're gonna have a baby.
我们要有孩子了
A baby?
孩子？
You sure?
你肯定？
You mad?
你疯了？
Mad?
疯了？
No. No.
没有
I ain't mad.
我没疯
"...as the eyes of the servants
作为仆人的眼睛
"look unto the hand of their masters
看向他们主人的双手
"and the eyes of a maid
女仆的眼睛
"look unto the hand of her mistress..."
看向她主人的双手
"...and Noah awoke from his wine
诺亚醒了酒
"and knew what his youngest son had done unto him.
知道了小儿子向他所做的事
"And he said,  'cursed be canaan.'"
他说到，迦南该受诅咒
"...servant of servants shall he be unto his brethren.
必给他弟兄做奴仆的奴仆
"And he said, blessed be the lord,
他说到，我们在天上的父神
"god of shem, and canaan..."
耶和华闪的神 愿迦南
Wait here.
等在这
I'll go check 'round back.
我去后面看下
Yessum.
好的
Whatcha doin' on my land?
你在我地盘干什么？
Hey! Call off your dog!
嗨，叫你的狗走开
No! He's with me!
不要，他和我一起的
Who the hell are you?
你他妈是谁？
I'm Samuel Turner. Reverend walthall sent us.
我是萨缪尔特纳，沃尔索尔教士派我们来的
Fella with the nigger preacher.
一个伙计和一个黑鬼牧师
Come on!
来吧
Let's go find Earl.
我们去找厄尔
You all right? Come on.
你还好吗？
Niggers is niggers here.
在这黑鬼就是黑鬼
Now, we don't treat none no different than another.
我们不会把他们当成其它人来对待
We got rules.
我们这有规矩
Cost of breakin' 'em, stealin', sassin',
偷窃，财产损失
or any other thing that Earl and I think
或者其它我和厄尔能想到的事情
worth dealin' with, will be paid for in skin.
任何的损失我们都会让他们遭到皮肉之苦
You interfere with that,
你要是干涉
we'll shoot you where you stand.
我们会向你开枪
Got any problem with that,
还有问题吗？
you can stop right now and go on back where you came from.
你也可以不干，从哪来回哪去
Come on now! Come on!
快点
Earl!
厄尔
This here is Sam Turner,
这是萨姆 特纳
fella with the nigger preacher.
还有个黑鬼牧师
Where you say you come from?
你说你从哪里来的？
We from here. Southampton county.
南安普顿乡
Just south of nottoway.
就在诺托韦的南面
Mmm.
嗯
Lotta Yankees makin' their way down that way.
罗塔 扬基 让他们走
Rabble-rousin', stirring shit on our way of life.
暴民们正在对我们的人生进行破坏
They're pullin' that same shit.
出同样问题了
Earl. Got a little problem.
厄尔，有个小麻烦
Which one? This one.
那个？这个
How long?
多久了？
Mmm. About a day or so.
大概一天左右
You ain't gonna eat, hmm?
你不吃饭？
You gonna eat? Come on. You ain't gonna eat?
你不吃饭，来吧
Hmm? Hmm? Hmm?
嗯？
All right.
好吧
If it ain't one thing, it's another.
这个不行，那就用另外的办法了
You wonderin' why we could use that nigger of yours?
你肯定疑惑我们为什么要用你黑鬼？
You're seein' it firsthand. All right, get his mouth open.
张开他的嘴
Well, if it ain't the yanks...
好的，美国佬
...it's the drought.
是干旱
If not the drought...
如果不是干旱
...it's goddamn mutiny.
是这该死的叛乱
Get a funnel in there.
把漏斗放这
Truth is, even the meanest nigger's
即便是黑鬼们所惧怕
fearful of the gospel.
的那些福音
Maybe a good word from your boy there,
从你的人嘴说出来也是最美好的话语
discipline word,go a lot furtherthan my pistol would.
这些话要比我的手枪更有用
Nat's a good preacher.
纳特是个好牧师
I don't right care how good he is,
我才不关心他的好坏
long as he say what he's supposed to.
关键是他支持什么
Brethren.
弟兄们
I pray you sing to the lord
我向上祈祷你们的罪过
a new song.
你们的罪过
Sing praise in assembly of the righteous.
歌颂义人在会中
Let the saints be joyful in glory.
愿圣民因所得的荣耀高兴
Let them sing aloud on their beds.
让他们大声歌唱
Let the high praise of god
高声赞美主
be on the mouths of the saints,
通过我们圣徒的口
and a two-edge sword in their hand
他们手中握着双刃剑
to execute vengeance on the demonic nations,
要斩断恶魔家园的复仇之火
and punishmenton those peoples
还要惩罚那些
to bind their kingswith chains
束缚住他们国王双眼
and their nobleswith fetters of iron
用枷锁捆绑住他们贵族的人们
to execute on them this written judgment.
去斩断他们，给予他们公正的审判
This honor hath all his saints!
荣誉属于他所有的圣徒
Praise the lord!
赞美主
Praise the lord! Sing to him a new song!
赞美主，歌颂他吧
Don't suppose you got a pass anywhere
不要想着穿这漂亮
underneath that pretty dress.
裙子到处乱走
No, sir.
没有，先生
I belongs to massa guiles and this here his property.
我是有主人的，这儿是他的私人领地
You sassin' me, girl?
你骗我？
No, sir.
没有
Anybody that knows nothin' knows that state law says
任何人都知道州法律的规定
that if a nigger's less than 10 paces from a tree line,
法律规定如果一个黑人出现在小于树木线十步的地方
that nigger need a pass.
那这个黑人需要通行证
Well, sir, I can get one.
好吧，先生，我可以拿到的
You ain't goin' nowhere.
你无处可去
Either you gonna show me a pass,
要么你给我看通行证
or you gonna show me somethin' else.
要不你给我看些其它的
What?
什么？
I'm sorry to disturb ya,
抱歉打扰了
but nat's gotta talk to you.
但是纳特有事对你说
Somethin' awful had happened.
发生了些可怕的事情
Whatever it is, just tell him
不管什么情况，告诉他
I'll get to it in the mornin'.
我早上会来这
Massa, if you could just see nat
主人，如果你能抽点时间
for just a moment, I...
见下纳特
Goddamnit, Isaiah.
见鬼了，艾塞亚
All right, tell him I'll meet him on the front porch.
好了，告诉他我会在前面走廊那见他
I'm right here, sir.
我就在这，先生
Might as well come in then.
进来吧
Sir, I am awfully sorry about all this. I...
先生，我对此十分抱歉
What is it, nat?
什么情况，纳特？
Cherry... she's been hurt real bad.
是切瑞，她受了很重的伤
Whatcha mean hurt?
什么伤？
A group of men, sir.
几个人，先生
Isaiah, fetch me some paper. Yeah.
艾塞亚，给我拿些纸来
All right, you should go down there.
好的，你下来吧
Take Jupiter, but don't start no trouble.
带上朱庇特，但不要惹麻烦
Stay the night, come back first thing in the morning.
呆一晚上，早上回来开始做事
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
好的，先生，谢谢了
God's gonna punish whoever did this.
上帝会惩罚那些人的
Monsters.
禽兽
Nat?
纳特？
I'm right here.
我在这
It's me now.
是我
I'm sorry.
对不起
No, no. You don't apologize.
不要，不需要道歉
You don't owe that to nobody.
你不要责怪自己
You need to tell me who done this to you.
告诉我是谁干的
'Cause I'm gonna take care of it, you hear?
我会处理的，你听见吗？
On my soul.
我的神啊
I need you to tell me now.
我需要你的指引
"Put up again thy sword into his place.
收刀入鞘吧
"For all they that take the sword
凡动刀的
"shall pass with the sword."
必死在刀下
You taught me that.
你曾经教过我
I need you here.
我需要你
Joanna, too.
乔安娜也需要
Leave this to the lord.
把这个留给上帝
You wanted to see me, sir?
你要见我，先生？
Yeah. How's cherry?
是的，切瑞怎么样了？
I'm believin' she'll be fine.
我相信她会好起来的
Good. Good.
那就好
Not many woulda let you go like I did.
我还能做些什么
Thank you, sir.
谢谢
Mmm.
嗯
We're having a big get-together tonight
我们今晚有个重要的活动
with a lot of very important people.
有很多重要人物出席
Kind of like when daddy was alive.
自从我父亲去世后就没有这样过
So I'm gonna need you and a couple of others in the house.
所以我需要你，还要几个人在这帮忙
Anyone who's had experience
还有谁能
servin' and being respectable help.
懂礼貌，服务好，有经验的
Yes, sir.
明白，先生
Can't tell ya how important this is for all of us.
能告诉我对您来说这些客人有多重要吗？
If we get this right,
如果我们做的好
the Turner name will mean something again.
那么意味着特纳的姓氏会再次崛起
Isaiah.
以赛亚
Yes, sir.
是，先生
As you all know, this annual dinner
就像你知道那样，这次年度晚宴
was a tradition of our daddy many years ago.
是我们的父亲多年来的传统
And for all he believed, he placed family, faith,
在他所有的崇尚中，家庭地位，信念
and tradition at the top of his priority list.
传统是他最为看重的东西
Twenty years later,
二十年后
those same priorities have kept this property afloat.
我们的财富正是因为有了这些相同的优先等级而得以保持
That and the cash down from your colored preacher.
那个和即期付款都是从你这个黑人牧师那来的
Yeah! That, too.
对的
May god continue to bless all of us
希望上帝可以世世代代
for many generations to come.
不停的祝福我们
Hear, hear.
对的
Nat, would you please lead us in prayer?
纳特，你可以带我们一起祷告吗？
Reverend, I trust you wouldn't mind.
尊敬的教士，我相信你不会介意的
I guess not.
我想不会
Heavenly father.
天父
We come to thank you for your word and your will.
我们前来感谢你的言行
We pray for and thank you
我们祈祷并且感谢你
for your protection and your promise.
为了你的保护与承诺
And in our obedience,
我们将顺从与你
you will be an enemy to our enemies.
你的敌人也将是我们的敌人
That you will oppose those who oppose us.
我们将反抗你所反抗的
Continue to guide us, o lord,
继续指引着我们，我的主啊
and we will continue to follow.
我们将继续跟随着你
Through fine tribulation we will push forward,
穿越磨难，勇往直前
recognizing only you as our source and strength.
认识到只有你才能作为我们的力量和源泉
In your holy name we pray.
我们将呼唤着你神圣的名字
Amen.
阿门
Bon appetit.
魔幻厨房
Daddy always said,
父亲总是说
"three black peppercorns in a glass of port,
三个黑胡椒放在一杯
"and you got yourself a excellent digestif."
这是最好的餐后酒
Well, black is always tasty.
不错，黑色总是引入入胜
Especially a nice piece of black meat. Sweet. Juicy.
特别是那块肉，多汁，甜美
I ain't doin' it, all right?
我不干，好吗？
Naw, naw. I need you to get out of here!
我需要你离开这
Ain't gonna happen, man. You just come out here...
办不到，你才刚一露面
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey! Ho, ho, ho!
嗨，嗨，嗨
What's goin' on, huh?
出什么事了？
- I ain't doin' it.  - Huh?
- 我不同意  - 嗯？
- I ain't doin' it, nat.  - Doin' what?
- 我不同意，纳特  - 什么情况？
He'd have to lynch me first.
他们要先对我用私刑
Lynch ya? What are we talkin' about?
私刑？我们在讨论什么东西？
One of Samuel's guests...
一个萨缪尔先生的客人
What?
什么？
One of Samuel's guests requested Esther, and, uh...
一个客人要求伊森
Just go and talk to Samuel. Just tell him what happened.
去找萨缪尔先生，告诉他发生了什么
Tell him what it was and he'll straighten this out.
告诉他，他会作出正确决定的
But Samuel sent me over here personally, nat.
但这是萨缪尔先生亲自派我来的
I can't do it, nat. I won't.
我不能这么做，纳特
Brother hark...
汉克兄弟
But, what... Who are you?
你是谁？
Brother hark, do you think
汉克兄弟，你觉得
that I wanna come over here for this?
我想为这个过来吗？
You here, ain't ya?
你听见了？
Nat!
纳特
Where is she?
她在哪里？
Samuel, sir. Please, you can't do this.
萨缪尔，先生，请不要这样做
Everything all right?
都还好吗？
Oh, it's just fine.
都还行
I'll be inside directly.
我会径直走进去的
I hope you won't be alone.
希望你不要孤单
I assure you, i will not be.
我保证你不会的
If you mess this up for me, my hand to god,
如果你把这个搞的一团糟，我发誓
I will lynch every one of you come mornin!
我会在第二天让你体无完肤
Do you understand me?
你明白我吗？
Fetch her.
把她带来
Yes, sir.
是，先生
It's okay.
没关系的
Where is he, nat? Where's god now?
他在那，纳特，神在哪？
Hark.
汉克
Excuse me.
对不起
I'm looking for a preacher named nat.
我在找一个叫纳特的牧师
He's been banned from every church
因为他的罪过
in the county for his sins.
他被这个国家的所有教堂都禁止出现了
He's lucky that's all he got for what he done.
对于他所做的事情，他已经是很幸运的了
The world has its way with dealing with the immoral.
世间对于不道德的交易有它自己的处理方式
Above all those who cast that immorality
重要的是谁来衡量发生
on the children as he has.
在他身上与孩子的这些不道德行为
But no one is without sin, miss Elizabeth.
但是我们所有人都是有罪的，伊丽莎白小姐
And this man wants to repent and be delivered.
这个男人需要忏悔，而且需要被指引
As a Shepherd of the lord, it's my duty to serve.
做为上帝的牧羊人，这是我的职责
So...
所以
I'd like to baptize him.
我想要为他洗礼
The hell you will!
见你的鬼
Jethro, you will mind your mouth.
杰斯罗，注意你的言辞
With respect, miss Elizabeth,
我很抱歉，伊丽莎白小姐
a nigger can't baptize no white man.
黑人不能为白人洗礼
I just think we should wait for Mr. Samuel to get back.
我只是认为我们应该等萨缪尔先生回来
Jethro, go wait in the front yard.
杰斯罗，去前院等着
Mr. Samuel gets back, he'll have both of us!
萨缪尔先生回来前有我们在
I won't ask you again.
我不会再说第二遍了
Boy, you gonna get it.
你等着
Are you sure you want to do this, nat?
你确定你要这么做吗，纳特？
Samuel may not like it.
萨缪尔不会喜欢这样做的
Nor will a lot of other folks around here.
现在有很多白人围在这附近
Don't got too much choice, missus.
不要考虑太多了，夫人
This man still belongs to god.
这个人依然属于神
When you stand between the lord and his people,
当你站在了上帝与它的子民之间
it's a dangerous place to be.
这会是个危险的境地
We've been good to you. My whole family has.
我们全家对你一直够好的
And you go on and do something like this to me.
你就是这样回报我的
A nigger baptizing a white man on my property!
一个黑人为一个白人洗礼，还是在我的地盘上
Do you know how this makes us look?
你知道这让我们看上去像什么吗？
This could ruin everything we worked for!
这会毁了我们所做的一切
Boy, you better say something and quick!
伙计，你最好快点解释下
"Take heed therefore unto yourselves,
圣灵立你们作为全群的监督
"and to all the flock over which
你们就当为自己谨慎
"the holy ghost hath made you overseers.
也为全群谨慎
"To feed the church of god
牧养神的教会
"which he has purchased with his own blood."
就是他用自己的血所买来的
Ex...
劝…
"Exhort servants
劝戒仆人
"to be obedient to thy own masters,
要顺服自己的主人
"and to please them well
凡事讨他的喜欢
"in all things not answering again..."
不可顶撞他
"You were bought with a price, do not become slaves of men."
你是被买来的不要成为人的奴仆
"He that shall blaspheme against the holy ghost
他会亵渎对抗圣灵
"hath never forgiveness, but is in danger..."
永远不会被原谅，但是非常危险
"Beware of false prophets
要防备假先知
"who come dressed in sheep's clothing,
就是那个披着羊皮的
"but inwardly are ravening wolves!"
但是内心确是贪婪饥饿的狼
You black bastard! Nat!
你个黑杂种，纳特
"He that stealeth a man and selleth him..."
他的秘密出卖了他
Don't you eyeball me, boy!
不要盯着我
"...or if he be found in his hand, he shall surely
或是如果他被发现在他的手里，他应该坚定无疑
"be put to death!"
被处以死刑
Get him to the post.
拉他去公示栏
Hey, boy.
嗨，伙计
If you make it out of this alive,
如果你活着熬过来了
I'm gonna ride you harder than hogs on slop.
我要让你日子更难过
Die.
去死吧
You learned your lesson, boy?
吸取教训了吗
Oh, yes, sir, I've learned.
是的，先生，我学到了
Go on, get him off.
把他放下来
You're done preachin' for a little while.
你完成布道有段时间了
And I don't want you runnin' off with any groups,
我也不喜欢你和其它组成员去到处瞎跑了
unless me and Jethro are there, you understand?
除非我和杰斯罗在的情况下，明白吗？
Yes, sir.
是，先生
All right, go and get yourself cleaned up.
好吧，去把自己弄干净些
Be back in the field come morning.
回田里工作吧
Brother, you all right?
兄弟，你还好吗？
Hey! Hey!
嗨，嗨
I watched your grandfather die
我看着你的祖父去世
in old land.
在老地方
Saw him give up the ghost with my own eyes.
亲眼看着他的灵魂升天
And he saw me.
他看着我
He harnessed the holy spirit that day.
他的灵魂在那天得到了升华
Yes, he did.
是的
I was proud of him.
我感到很自豪
So proud.
非常自豪
I still thank god
我依旧感谢着神灵
that he died that day.
就在他死的那天
That he didn't live to see the things I seen.
他没有活着看见这些，而我看见了
To watch a strong man broken down
看着一个坚强的人被打倒
is a terrible thing.
被一些可怕的事情
Hey, Nana.
嗨，奶奶
The stitches held up good.
伤口缝合的还不错
Nana?
奶奶
You all right?
你还好吗？
Mostly.
最主要的
I need you to round up a few men you trust.
我需要你聚集一些你信得过的人
Have them meet us at the big cypress
让他们与我们在柏树林那见面
at cabin pond night after next.
就在小屋池塘那后天晚上
Hark.
哈克
He's still here, brother.
他还在这，兄弟
Even now.
尽管这样
This is Simon.
这是西蒙
Samuel bought him a month back in Norfolk.
萨缪尔回来一个月后买了他，在诺福克
I remember. Welcome, brother.
我记得，欢迎，兄弟
And you know Nelson.
你认识尼尔森
Welcome.
欢迎
This is will.
这是威尔
Word travels fast. Welcome.
世界变化真快，欢迎
Hey! This grown folk's business! Get! Get!
嗨，这是大人们的事情，走开了
Hold on.
慢点
Come on over here.
过来这
Come from Randall's? Yes, sir.
从兰德尔来的？是，先生
He's just a boy.
他还是个孩子
So was David.
大卫也是
Come on. Have a seat.
来吧，坐下
I've been following the lord a long time.
我已经追随了上帝很长时间了
Preachin', citing scripture,
布道，引用圣经
sharing the gospel from the few pages
从几页篇章里分享福音
and sections I've been allowed.
而且我也认同里面的部分内容
But I've gone back through this word, all of it.
但是回到这个现实世界，所有这一切
With new eyes.
用一种新的方式来看待的话
I see now, for every verse
在我现在看来，这些诗篇
they use to support our bondage,
都是他们用来作为奴役我们枷锁
there's another demanding our freedom.
我们的自由在这看起来是一种苛求
Every verse they use to justify our torture,
每一个篇章都被他们证明现在对我们的这些折磨是合理依法的
there's another damning them to hell for those actions.
而这些奴隶主的行为也不会轻易被下地狱
Lord has spoken to me. Visions of what's to come.
上帝告诉我，接下去我们要开拓眼界
A rise of good against evil.
要用善良来对抗邪恶
The first shall be last, and the last shall be first.
有人想做首先，他必做众人末后
Brothers, we've been chosen.
兄弟们，我们是被选中的
What are we gonna do?
我们要干什么？
Same as David and Gideon
做大卫和基甸
and Joshua and Samson.
约书亚和参孙
We'll fight. The six of us?
我们要战斗，就我们六个人？
At first. But once it begins,
开始是这样，但是一旦开始了
our brothers and sisters will join.
我们兄弟姐妹就会加入
There's a whole lot of whites.
这儿可是有很多白人的
How many slaves you think there are in the county?
在这个国家有多少奴隶？
On all the plantations? How many whites?
所有的种植园里有多少？白人又有多少？
But they got guns.
但是他们有枪
We'll take the armory in Jerusalem.
我们将夺取耶路撒冷的军火库
We'll have guns, too.
我们也会有枪的
Jerusalem?
耶路撒冷？
That's right. It's only 10 miles north.
对的，就在北方十英里的地方
We'll start right here at Turner's
我们就从特纳这里开始
and fight our way there.
打出我们自己的天下
By then we'll number in the hundreds,
到时我们就有几百人
thousands even.
甚至上千人
The grapevine's ablaze with talks of fightin'.
星星之火可以燎原
Slaves all over havin' meetins'.
奴隶制结束了
They waitin' on something.
他们在等待
They waitin' on us.
等我们的召唤
We make a stop at Fowler place?
我们在富勒的地方停留
We will.
可以
I'm with you.
我加入
Me, too.
我也是
- When we fight?  - Soon.
- 我们什么时候战斗？ - 很快
The lord will give us a sign.
上帝会给我启示的
Until then we remain steadfast,
在这之前我们要保持坚定
ready to strike at the moment of the lord's call.
做好准备等待上帝的召唤
With the strength of our father,
带着我们强大的信念
we'll cut the head from the serpent.
我们会最终获胜的
We'll destroy them all.
我们会全部摧毁他们
Somethin' wrong?
有什么不对吗？
There was a meeting a few nights ago.
前几天晚上有个会议
And although I was not privy to what was said,
虽然我不知道说了些什么
I can only assume
我只能靠假设
by the secrecy that it was not altogether productive.
秘密不能让太多人知道
Now,  I don't know what ideas
现在，我不明白意思
is floatin' around  in your head,
在你的脑海四周飘荡
but I been around here  long enough to know
但是我就在你周围，足够了解你
that the result of certain ideas
确信无疑的结果
is not gonna get you what you want.
不会让你随心所欲的
All I want,
我想要的
I want for the oppressed people of god.
我想代表神为了被压迫的人们
You want death for them?
你愿意为他们去死？
For your wife?
为了你妻子？
For your daughter?
为了你女儿？
If it be god's will.
如果这是神的旨意
God's will?
神的旨意
And who determined you
谁让你这么坚决
to be the instrument of such a thing?
为了这样的事情而成为一个工具？
He has.
他
You just make sure that he's the one doin' the orderin'.
你确定
Man of god is called to lead in love.
神的仆人被称为爱的领路人
Anything else will leave us all worse off.
所有都会离我们而去
He is a god of love, nat.
他是爱的神，纳特
Don't you forget that.
不要忘记了
I won't.
我不会
Nor will I forget he's a god of wrath.
我会忘记他是愤怒的神
Mmm...
妈妈
The lord's calling me.
上帝在召唤我
To stand and fight.
去战斗
I knew this day would come.
我知道这天终会来到
I told myself i wouldn't be scared.
我告诉自己不要害怕
All my life,
我的有生之年
I've been praying for the lord to help us
都在祈祷上帝能帮助我们
or to send someone who could.
或者派个救世主来拯救我们
We all have.
我们所有人都这样
Just wasn't expecting it to be my own husband.
只是没曾想盼来的确是我丈夫
If the lord's called you to fight,
如果是上帝召唤你去战斗
you fight.
你就去
You fight for me,
你为我而战
and Joanna.
还有乔安娜
You fight for us all.
为了我们所有人
Hmm?
嗯？
Who's there?
谁在那？
Nat?
纳特？
Yes.
是的
Wait, goddamnit!
等着，他妈的
Damn it!
可恶
Momma?
母亲？
Momma.
母亲
Nat? Oh lord, i slept too late.
纳特？哦，上帝，我睡的太晚了
No, no... Momma.
没有，母亲
You won't have to work today.
你今天不用干活了
You free.
你自由了
The battle's begun, ma.
战役开始
Simon.
西蒙
Simon will take you to Reese's.
西蒙会带你去里斯那里
And I need you to take care of cherry and Joanna
我要你照顾好切瑞和乔安娜
'till I get back, you hear?
知道我回来，好吗？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Nothing.
没事
I'm proud of you.
我为你自豪
What did you do, boy? Huh?
你做了什么？
Huh? You killed them, boy?
你杀了他们？
Is that what you did?
是你干的吗？
ou kill them and you kill us!
你杀了他们，你等于杀了我们
You killed all of us.
你等于杀了我们所有人
We already dead. We already dead!
我们死定了
You dead.
你死定了
We dead now!
我们要死了
Your
你们
earthly master is gone.
之前的主人已经不在了
You're now free men and women,
你们是自由的男人和女人
servants of only the lord.
只服务与上帝
As the sword of the lord bears down on our enemies,
就像上帝之剑赦免我们的敌人一样
our ancestors and unborn children rejoice.
让我们的祖先和未出生的孩子高兴吧
Are we dead?
我们死了吗？
No. I say we are now alive,
没有，我说大家都活着
seeing through eyes that have been denied us
透过这些眼睛看到的
since being born into the darkness of bondage.
自从出生以来就在受压迫和黑暗的日子里
Stand with us.
与我们站在一起
Let your other captive brothers and sisters
让你们那些被抓获的兄弟姐妹们
also know freedom.
也知道自由的滋味
Stand that our children
与我们的孩子在一起
for generations to come will know
让他们世代都知道
that with the supernatural power of god,
神的伟大与奇妙
we straightened our backs
我们挺直自己的脊梁
against the works of the evil one!
对抗邪恶
Stand with us.
与我们在一起
Can I do this myself?
我能自己做吗？
The boy! He gone!
孩子，他走了
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
呼呼
Get down!
趴下
Hey, preacher!
嗨，牧师
Hark!
汉克
Are you out there?
你在外面？
Tell the men to fall back.
告诉那个人后退
What?
什么？
If we have a gun battle now,
如果我们现在发生枪战
we'll never make it to Jerusalem.
我们就永远到不了耶路撒冷
Me and my boys is ready!
我和我的人准备好了
I want my revenge!
我要复仇
This ain't about revenge, hark!
这不是复仇
You all gonna hang! You hear me?
你们都要被吊死，你听见了吗？
All of ya!
所有人
The root,
祖先
not the branch.
不要有分歧
We must stay focused, brother.
我们必须保持专注，兄弟
Will! Fall back! C'mon! C'mon, y'all. C'mon.
撤退
Let's fall back, y'all!
让我们撤退
You all right?
你还好吗？
It's all of us.
我们所有人
This it?
就这？
Hark, what time you think it is?
哈克，你觉得现在几点了？
5:30, 5:35.
五点三十，五点三十五
What?
什么？
By now I'd be two rows down,
现在我会两排下来
half a bag full.
半袋
I'd be headed to the barn,
我将前往谷仓
gettin' ready to feed the stock.
准备喂牲口
I'd be boiling water in the smokehouse,
我要去烟熏室烧开水
thinkin' 'bout dumping on massa's head.
倒在那些主人的头上
I'd be tying the barrels, sealin' cracks.
我将捆绑木桶，填补裂缝
Checkin' the leaves and straw.
记录着树叶与稻草
Packin' and stackin' 'em up.
包装和消磨这一切
Dodgin' that cracker's lash.
避开爆竹的飞屑
Not today.
但不是今天
No, sir.
对的，先生
On to Jerusalem?
去向耶路撒冷？
All right, this is how this is gonna work.
好了，接下去你们应该这么办
You're gonna throw the weapons to the ground,
把武器丢在地上
then you're gonna lie down.
接着趴在地上
Do it.
快点
The lord is our light and our salvation.
上帝是我们的明灯，是我们的救世主
Of whom we shall fear?
我们应该怕谁？
Throw your weapons to the ground!
把你们的武器丢在地上
The lord is the strength of our lives.
我们要相信上帝的强大
Of whom shall we be afraid?
我们应该要害怕谁？
When the wicked, even our enemies
当邪恶，甚至仇敌
and our foes came upon us
还有我们的敌人来到面前
to eat up our flesh, they stumbled and fell!
要生吞活剥了我们时，他们只会失败跌倒
Goddamn, niggers.
他妈的，黑鬼们
Though a host shall encamp against us,
虽然你们这些主人反对我们有安生之所
our hearts will not fear!
但是我们的心将不会感到恐惧
Ready!
准备
Though war shall rise against us,
虽然战争会影响我们
in this we will be confident!
但在这方面我们有信心
Aim!
瞄准
Rebel!
叛乱者
Come on!
来吧
Get down!
趴下
Will!
好的
Get back!
回来
I'm all right.
我没事
Cherry.
切瑞
It's nat, love.
是纳特，亲爱的
Keep on workin'.
不要停
They lookin' for you.
他们在找你
They hurt you?
他们伤了你？
No.
么有
How's Joanna?
乔安娜怎么样？
She fine.
她很好
Momma?
母亲？
She fine, too.
她也很好
Keep on workin' now.
手上不要停
Any word on the other men?
其他人怎么样了？
They been hanged.
他们被吊死了
All of them.
所有人
They killin' people everywhere
他们在到处杀人
for no reason at all but being black.
没有理由就因为你是黑人
They say the killin' won't stop
他们说了会一直杀下去
'till they get you.
直到抓到你
All these months
这几个月来
I thought...
我想过
I thought you were dead, too.
你是不是也死了
I'm here, love.
我就在这，亲爱的
I'll always be.
我一直都在这
I miss you so much.
我太想你了
Cherry?
切瑞？
Who you talkin' to?
你在和谁说话？
I's just talkin' to myself.
我在自言自语
Wishin' things was different.
多希望这些事情会有所不同啊
Hey!
嗨
That's him right there!
那是他
Kill that nigger!
杀了那个黑鬼
I know you're angry. Trust me, I am too.
我知道你很愤怒，相信我，我也是的
This boy committed mass murder and will hang for all to see.
这个孩子犯下了屠杀罪，我们将当众吊死他
Get him up.
拉他起来
Go to hell!
下地狱去
Animal!
禽兽
Hang him!
吊死他
Is there something you wanna say
还有什么要对
to these good people?
这些善良人们说的吗？
I'm ready.
我准备好了